Finding Aid for Lynn W. Eley papers, 1958-1963
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lynn W. Eley papers 1958-1963
Eley, Lynn W.
3 linear feet
851161 Aa 2
Professor of political science at University of Michigan, and Democratic city councilman for Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1961-1963. Material concerning his council activities, his work for the Michigan Advisory Committee on Reorganization of State Government, and the Michigan State Science Advisory Board.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Lynn Eley (donor no. 4180 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Lynn Eley was born Oct. 23, 1925 in Zearing, Iowa. He received a B.A. in 1949 from Harvard and a M.A. in 1951 and a Ph. D. in 1952 from the State University of Iowa.
Eley joined the University of Michigan faculty in 1955 as research associate in the Institute of Public Administration. He later became a faculty member in the department of political science. Beyond his University work, Eley served as secretary of the Governor's Advisory Committee on Reorganization of State Government from 1958 to 1962. He was also one of two University representatives on the Michigan Coordinating Council of State College Field Services created by the Council of State College Presidents in 1959. From 1961 to 1963, Eley served one term as a member of the Ann Arbor City Council representing the First Ward.
The Lynn Eley collection documents his activities as secretary on the Governor's Advisory Committee on Reorganization of State Government, 1958-1963, and his term as Democratic Ann Arbor City Councilman, 1961-1963.
Subjects:
African Americans--Michigan.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.). Common Council.; Civil rights--Michigan.; Democratic Party (Mich.); Michigan. Advisory Committee on Reorganization of State Government.; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Michigan. State Science Advisory Board.; Municipal government--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Political Science.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
- Correspondence June 1958-1963
  - June-September 1958 (Box 1)
  - October-December 1958 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1959 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1959 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1960 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1960 (Box 1)
  - 1961 (Box 1)
  - 1962 (Box 1)
  - 1963 (Box 1)
- Science Advisory Committee
  - Minutes 1958-1959 (Box 1)
- Advisory Committee on Reorganization of State Government 1958-1963 t
  - Minutes 1958-1961 (Box 1)
  - Reports and papers (primarily the Advisory Committee on Reorganization of State Government)
    - 1958 (Box 1)
    - 1959 (Box 1)
    - 1960 (Box 1)
    - 1961 (Box 1)
    - 1962 (Box 1)
    - 1963 (Box 1)
  - Topical files
    - Reports from legislative departments concerning revision of the Michigan Constitution. (Box 1)
    - Article 1958, concerning constitutional revision in Michigan (Box 1)
    - Miscellanea 1958, concerning executive reorganization (Box 1)
    - Speech 1958, of Eley entitled "Present Constitution and Need of Reform" (Box 1)
    - Speech 1959, of Eley given before House State Affairs Committee (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous speeches concerning executive reorganization (Box 1)
    - Plans and drafts for revising the constitution (Box 1)
- Ann Arbor City Council Files 1961-1966
  - Administrative Procedure of Regulatory Agencies 1963 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Airport Advisory Committee 1962 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Civic Theatre Workshop 1962 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor School Board 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Campaign for City Council 1961 (Box 1)
  - Campaign for City Council 1963 (Box 1)
  - City Charter Reform 1963 (Box 1)
  - City Hall Building 1962 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Edison Company 1962 (Box 1)
  - Dutch Elm Disease in Ann Arbor (Box 1)
  - Fair Housing Ordinance 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - Man Power Commission 1963, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea 1962-1963 (Box 2)
  - Municipal Income Tax 1962 (Box 2)
  - Northbelt By-Pass 1960-1963 (Box 2)
  - Police and Fire Needs 1962, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Sky Walk 1962 (Box 2)
  - Sunday Closing Ordinance 1962 (Box 2)
  - Taxicab Board 1961, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - University of Michigan. Oxford Housing Project 1962 (Box 2)
  - University of Michigan. Zoo Closing, 1962. (Box 2)
  - Zoning and Planning 1961-1962, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Capital Improvements Program 1962-1967, Ann Arbor (Box 2)
  - Paper 1964, regarding civil rights in Ann Arbor (Box 2)
- Scrapbooks and clippings
  - Scrapbooks concerning Ann Arbor city government and Eley's activities on the city council 1961-1963, 4 volumes (Box 3)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - 1958-1959 (Box 3)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 3)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 3)